Oh, they're going at it.
噢,他們真的打起來了
This way, Your Highness.
這裡,公主殿下
His Majesty and Sir Wulf are here.
陛下和沃爾夫先生在這裡
You're right.
真的耶
Is that really Canute?
那真的是庫奴爾嗎?
I can't believe he dodged that.
真不敢相信他躲過了
King Canute is quite impressive.
庫奴特王真有兩把刷子
How can he move in that armor?
穿著盔甲怎麼還能夠這麼敏捷?
Those are real swords, right?
那些是真的劍,對吧?
Yes, I believe so.
嗯,我覺得是真的
Is this really training?
這真的是在訓練嗎?
He'll get injured badly if he's hit.
如果被擊中的話,他會傷得很重
- Look at him working so hard. - Gunnar!
-看看他那股拚勁 -君納爾
Hello, Lady Estrid. How are you enjoying your day?
妳好,艾絲特莉小姐 今天過得好嗎?
I'm not enjoying it at all!
一點都不好
This is so scary. I'm worried sick.
這太可怕了,我擔心死了
Please be assured. Wulf is a master swordsman.
請妳放心,沃爾夫是劍術大師
He is controlling his power so that nothing happens.
他會好好控制力道,不會出差錯的
It doesn't look like that to me.
在我看來不是那樣
I can't believe this.
這真的是太誇張了
Canute used to hate even touching a sword.
庫奴特以前很討厭劍,連碰都不碰
His Majesty awakened his royal blood while in England.
陛下在英格蘭喚醒了他的皇室魂
It is very commendable.
非常值得讚許
A king must be strong above anything else.
國王最重要的特質就是強壯
Nordic men will not
一名弱者說出來的話
listen to the words of a weak man.
北方人絕對不會買單
But he looks
但他看起來...
like he is in a lot of pain.
一副很痛苦的樣子
You retreat when you are tired. It's a bad habit of yours.
你累了就會退縮,這是你的壞習慣
When you retreat it only prolongs the fight.
當你開始退縮,只會拖長打鬥的時間
A true king advances and finds a way out
一位真正的國王會進攻,想辦法
with his sword.
用劍找到出路
Not only are your enemies watching, but your own subjects
不僅您的敵人正在看,您的子民
are observing how you wield your sword as well.
也在看你如何揮舞你的劍
And Estrid is also watching.
艾絲特莉也在看
You've noticed, haven't you?
你注意到了,對吧?
I see...
原來如此
So that is why you started to attack with more force
所以你才會突然開始用
all of a sudden.
更大的力道攻擊
Th... There you go again.
您...又來了
I will not fall for that trick!
我才不會上您的當
Forget it. I didn't mean that.
算了,我不是那個意思
And plus, she's too busy talking to the man next to her.
況且,她正忙著跟旁邊的人聊天
You win.
你贏了
Wow!
哇
That was amazing!
真是太精采了
Wow, I'm so surprised.
我太驚訝了
The score was five to one, but he actually made Wulf admit defeat.
比數是五比一 但他竟然讓沃爾夫認輸了
Wulf seemed to be distracted at the end, didn't he?
沃爾夫到最後似乎分心了,對吧?
Your Majesty, I've told you many times that you must not
陛下,我已經告訴過您很多次了
toss your sword like that.
您不該那樣扔您的劍
That was an amazing duel, Your Majesty.
這場決鬥真精采,陛下
What is it, Gunnar?
那是什麼,君納爾?
We've completed the paperwork regarding the survey.
調查報告已經完成了
I will bring it to your chamber later.
稍候我會帶去您的寢宮
I must say, there aren't many wealthy people out there.
我得說那裡的有錢人不多
Even if you were to squeeze the people on that list dry
儘管你有辦法把名單上的人吃乾抹淨
you would only get about 3,000 pounds per year.
一年最多也只有三千磅
Other than that,
除此之外
the only option would be to raise the taxes in general.
唯一的辦法只有提高賦稅了
Oh, I recommend that one.
噢,我建議這一位
Ketil, son of Sverkel.
斯威克的兒子,凱特爾
He is a wealthy farmer who owns a massive estate in the south.
他是個很富裕的農夫 在南方擁有一大片土地
The military power of each family is not listed on here.
每戶的武力並未列在表上
Yes...
對...
For that we would have to go there and investigate in person.
要取得這項資料的話 我們必須親自到府訪察
I need to know those numbers. Investigate and update me.
我得知道詳細的數字 調查之後回報給我
Yes, of course.
好的,沒問題
However, this will be a significant tax increase immediately following
但是,在您加冕為丹麥國王之後
your coronation as the King of Denmark.
立刻就提高賦稅
I am more worried
我更擔心
about the backlash from the people of Denmark.
這會引來丹麥人民的反彈
Making sure that that doesn't happen is what politics is all about.
確保這種事不會發生 這就是政治家該做的事
It's not impossible.
並非不可能
After his accession to the throne of England,
庫奴特在成為英格蘭國王後
Canute was faced with a pressing issue.
立刻就得面臨一個迫切的難題
That was obtaining a new source of funds.
要找出新的資金來源
Even after conquering England,
儘管征服了英格蘭
Canute kept his personal troop of Danish warriors stationed there.
庫奴特仍然要求個人的 丹麥戰士部隊駐守在那裡
However, that troop was being funded
但是,部隊的花費
by the tax revenue collected from England.
全仰賴英格蘭的稅收
This contributed to the growing dissatisfaction among the English people.
導致英格蘭人民愈來愈不滿意
If Canute cannot manage to scrape up the funds from within
如果庫奴特無法從他最新取得的領地
Denmark, his newly acquired dominion,
也就是丹麥境內找到財源
he has no choice but to scale down his stationed army.
他別無選擇,只能裁軍
It's not impossible? What options do we have?
不是不可能?我們還有什麼選擇?
We'll acquire more crown land.
我們可以取得更多的皇室土地
You're going to reclaim land?
您打算開墾土地?
But that will take time until we gain a profit from it.
但我們得等上一段時間 才能從土地上獲利
I will gain more fields
我會用開墾以外的方式
in ways other than reclamation.
取得更多土地
You mean by requisition?
您的意思是徵地?
Your Majesty, that is going a bit far...
陛下,這樣有點過分...
We need money. We will have to take some drastic measures.
我們需要錢,得採取一些激烈的手段
At least it's better than
至少比增加賦稅
sowing seeds of discontent throughout the nation by increasing the tax.
在全國播下不滿的種子來得好吧?
If you have a better plan, I am all ears.
如果你有更好的辦法,我洗耳恭聽
Why don't we just dissolve the corps at this point?
我們何不直接裁軍呢?
That's out of the question.
沒有這個選項
I am a conqueror and a Dane.
我是征服者,而且是丹麥人
The people of England don't think favorably of me.
英格蘭人民對我沒什麼好感
The effectiveness of my rulership depends on
我能否鞏固我統治者的地位
whether or not I have a corps that will do my will.
端看我是否有一個 能夠聽命於我的軍隊
A king is a sword.
國王就是劍
In a world like this, a king without military power can't accomplish anything.
處在這樣的世界 沒有武力的國王完成不了任何事
What?
什麼?
King Harald passed away?
哈羅德國王駕崩了?
One week ago. You were just a bit too late, Dad.
一週前的事了,你來晚了一點,爸
Wh... That means
也就是說...
by the time I left the farm he was already...
我離開農場時,他就已經...
I guess so.
我想是吧
I didn't know his health was that bad.
我不知道他的病情這麼嚴重
This is unbelievable.
真令人不敢相信
And here, I brought a mountain of gifts for him.
我還為他帶來了堆積如山的禮物
Three knarr's worth, huh?
整整三船的禮物啊?
How ambitious of you.
你的野心還真大
Wait a second, Thorgil...
等等,托爾吉爾...
The fact that you are here to welcome me
你在這裡迎接我
means King Canute is here as well, right?
就表示庫奴特王也在這裡,對吧?
Well, I am King Canute's thegn after all.
當然囉,我可是他的臣子
Right now, His Majesty is at the palace on behalf of the king.
陛下目前是代理國王,正待在宮中
I see. I guess I found a silver lining.
是喔,我想我有了一線希望
Now that I don't have the backing of King Harald,
我現在沒有了哈羅德國王的支持
I need to build a good relationship with
我得和下一任的丹麥王國
the next king of Denmark.
建立起友好關係
Can you somehow put me in touch with His Majesty?
你可不可以想個辦法 讓我見陛下一面?
You sure have a tough spirit. Okay, I'll take care of it.
你還真是不屈不撓啊 好吧,就交給我吧
Okay, I'm counting on you.
那好,就看你的囉
Olmar!
歐瑪
Hey, where did Olmar go?
嘿,歐瑪跑去哪了?
Oh, the young master just took off on his own and went into town.
少主自己一個人進城了
You let him go?
你就讓他走了?
I told you to keep an eye on him!
我不是叫你看好他嗎?
Come on, Dad.
別這樣啦,爸
He's already 20 years old. He's not a child anymore.
他已經20歲了,不是個孩子了
He is a child!
他就是個孩子
That idiot is forever just a child.
那個笨蛋永遠長不大
Just imagine him going into town alone.
他一個人進城,光是用想的我就...
I bet you anything he's in a fight right now
跟你打賭,他現在肯定鬧事了
because someone bumped into him
原因只不過是有人撞到他
and they didn't apologize or something like that!
但沒有跟他道歉這種小事
You're the one who bumped into me, you jerk!
是你撞到我的,渾球
Don't try to fool with me.
少給我裝蒜
You're the one who has to apologize.
該道歉的人是你
Excuse me?
你說什麼?
What are you talking about?
這是什麼鬼話?
Look at what you've done! I was going to sell this cloth!
看看你做的好事 我本來打算拿這些布料去賣
Why should I care?
關我什麼事?
If this is a ruse to make me buy it, I'm not falling for it.
如果這是要我買下它的詭計 我才不會上當
What? How rude of you to think that!
什麼?你怎麼會有這麼低級的想法?
But I will have you pay compensation, though.
但我得要你付我賠償金就是了
Now you're showing your true colors.
你露出真面目了吧
That was your plan from the start, huh? You're a fraud.
這就是你一開始的打算,對吧? 你這個騙子
- My goodness... - You bastard...
-我的天 -混帳東西
How did your parents raise you to be such a difficult person?
你父母怎麼會教出你這種惡霸?
I am known
大家都知道
to be an upstanding businessman just like my father!
我跟我父親一樣都是正直的商人
- I will not allow you to insult us. - Huh?
-我絕不會讓你侮辱我 -是嗎?
What are you going to do about it?
那你打算怎麼做?
Want to fight me? Just try me.
想打架嗎?有種就試試看
You "crash for cash" scammer.
“假撞人真騙錢”的騙子
I've had enough! You jerk!
我受夠了,你這個渾球...
He took out his sword.
他拿出劍了
What's wrong? Come and get me, you scammer.
怎麼了嗎?來打我呀,你這個騙子
Are you scared? Huh?
你怕了嗎?是嗎?
That's not fair!
這不公平
"Not fair"?
不公平?
When a man starts a fight,
一個男人挑起了爭鬥
he puts his life on the line.
就得冒上生命危險
The fact that you don't have a weapon ready at all times,
你竟然沒有隨身帶著劍
means that you don't have the preparedness
就表示你沒資格當一個...
of a Nordic man!
北方人!
Then tell me...
那你告訴我
Who do you think bought you that "preparedness"?
你的“資格”是誰買給你的?
Huh?
什麼?
You idiot!
你這個笨蛋
Why do you always have to start fights like this!
你為什麼就愛惹事生非?
What the heck, old man!
搞什麼呀?你這個老頭子
Don't butt into a man's fight!
我要打架,你不要管
Look, I'm sorry.
聽好,我很抱歉
Let me compensate you for that cloth.
讓我賠償你的損失
Is this enough?
這樣夠嗎?
Well, if you say so... I don't mind.
呃...如果你堅持的話,我就收下囉
Hey, Bug-Eyes!
喂,蟲眼
Give him back his change!
把錢還給他
Oh, Dad... You were watching?
爸...你一直都在看?
I saw everything.
我全都看到了
I was watching you in hopes that you would
我在旁邊觀察你,希望你能
defuse the situation, but what a disappointment.
化解這場糾紛,但你太讓我失望了
I guess you're still not ready for big transactions yet.
我看你仍然沒準備好做大買賣
Sorry...
對不起啦
I apologize on behalf of my son.
我代我兒子跟你道歉
My name is Leif Ericson.
我叫雷夫瑞克森
Oh, he's your adopted son?
他是你領養的?
Yes, basically...
對,基本上...
He ended up at my place by chance.
因緣際會,他最後住進了我家
Come on, introduce yourself.
快點,自我介紹一下
I'm Thorfinn. Thank you for earlier.
我叫托爾芬,之前謝謝你了
Everyone calls me Bug-Eyes, so please call me that too.
大家都叫我蟲眼,你也叫我蟲眼吧
Thorfinn?
托爾芬?
Oh, sorry.
啊,抱歉
It just reminded me of my servant with the same name.
我剛好想到我有個僕人也叫這個名字
He is a quiet, earnest, and hardworking fellow.
他是一個安靜、認真和勤奮的傢伙
Maybe I should've named this one Thorfinn as well.
也許我也該叫他改名成托爾芬
Well, your son seems to be very fearless.
你兒子看起來似乎非常勇敢
Say, Ketil... If you don't mind me asking,
是說,凱特爾,冒昧請教一下
is this Thorfinn... I mean, your servant,
這個托爾芬...我是說你的僕人
a slave by any chance?
他是個奴隸嗎?
Huh? Yes...
呃...對
How did you know?
你怎麼知道的?
I didn't want you to take it the wrong way so I didn't mention his status.
我不想讓你誤會 所以我沒提起他的身分
Is he Nordic, blond, brown-eyed,
他是金髮藍眼的北方人?
and about the same age and build as him?
差不多跟他同樣歲數、同樣體型?
How surprising! That's exactly right.
太神奇了,還真的是這樣
He is a bit shorter, though.
他比較矮一點就是了
That again, Dad?
又來了,爸?
He is from Iceland and used to be a warrior, no?
他來自冰島 而且曾是一名戰士,對吧?
So... Did he ever mention that?
這個嘛...他說過這些事嗎?
I have seen countless sword wounds on his body, though.
我倒是見過他身上有數不清的刀傷
You shouldn't get your hopes up. It'll end up like it did with me.
你不該有太高的期望 不然又會出現另外一個我
I know. I know that,
我知道啦
but all of his traits match up this far.
但目前這些特徵都很符合
You seem to have a story, Leif.
你似乎有什麼隱情,雷夫
If you don't mind, please tell me.
如果你不介意的話,不妨告訴我
Yes, well...
好的...
I am searching
我一直在尋找
for my friend's son who became a slave.
我朋友的兒子,他成了一名奴隸
It's been many years already.
已經好多年了
Where did you say?
你說哪裡?
Uh, well, you see... I was thinking
是這樣的啦,我想說...
about quickly stopping by Ketil's farm.
去拜訪一下凱特爾的農場,快去快回
It's really not that far, I swear.
沒有很遠啦,我發誓
Ketil also came by boat.
凱特爾也是坐船來的
And he said we can follow him home.
他說我們可以跟著他回家
How long is a one-way trip from here?
從裡出發,單程要多久才會抵達?
He said with fair winds, it takes five days.
他說風勢穩定的話,要五天
That means we'll lose more than ten days! That's more than just a quick stop.
那就表示我們會損失超過十天 這才不算快去快回
Please listen, Mord.
請聽我說,莫爾茲
There's something different about this time's "Thorfinn."
這次的”托爾芬”有些特別之處
I feel like it's the one!
我覺得就是他了
It's already fall!
已經秋天了
We have to hurry back or the Greenland Sea will freeze!
我們得趕快打道回府 不然格陵蘭海要結凍了
What are you going to do if we
如果我們將行程延後十天
delay our schedule for ten days and meet bad winds and tides?
然後遇上了大風大浪,你要怎麼辦?
Sorry, but I can't humor you this time.
很抱歉,但這次我無法將就你
Please understand.
請你明白
I'm so surprised.
我太驚訝了
I just put in a request yesterday, and I'm already granted an audience?
我昨天才提出要求 今天就能夠晉見陛下?
I didn't know you were so influential, Thorgil.
我不知道你這麼有影響力,托爾吉爾
I have newfound respect for you.
我更佩服你啦
Honestly, I am surprised as well.
老實說,我也很驚訝
His Majesty is a really busy person.
陛下真的很忙
Maybe your tribute did the trick?
或許你的貢品真的起了作用?
That is understandable.
這也是合情合理
We produce the best and most abundant crops in the southern region.
我們生產的穀物,不管是品質 還是產量都是南方第一
Even the king will not regret doing business with us.
就連國王也不會後悔和我們做生意
Ketil and company, enter the audience chamber.
凱特爾一行人請上殿
All right, let's go, Olmar.
好的,走吧,歐瑪
Mind your manners.
注意禮數
Ketil, I took a look at your offerings.
凱特爾,我看了你的貢品
They were all of very high quality. I will accept them.
品質皆屬上等,我會收下
Thank you, I am greatly honored.
謝謝,這實在是我的榮幸
Were all of those products
那些產品
produced on your farm?
都來自於你的農場?
Yes, that is correct.
對,沒錯
The late King Harald was also very fond of our family's products.
已故的哈羅德王 也很喜歡我們家的農產品
I do not plan on pointlessly changing the ways of my father and brother.
我不打算隨隨便便 就改變我父親和我哥哥的作風
Be assured.
你儘管放心
Prosperous farmers such as yourself are treasures to Denmark.
像你這樣多產的農夫是丹麥的寶藏
Take pride
你該引以為傲
in the fact that you are a cornerstone of the nation and keep on working diligently.
因為你是國家的基石,請繼續努力
I am honored.
我太榮幸了
I deeply appreciate your continued support.
您願意繼續支持我,我真的感激不盡
You are in the presence of the king. Kneel down!
你正在參見陛下,跪下
Hey! What are you doing?
喂,你在做什麼?
I am terribly sorry!
我真的很抱歉
King Canute! I have a favor to ask!
庫奴特王,我有個請求
Please let me join your corps!
請讓我加入您的軍隊
Preferably, as a thegn, like my brother.
最好像我哥哥一樣,成為臣子
I have been training.
我一直在受訓
I will be useful.
我會很有用處的
I can show you my skill here--
我立刻就可以讓您看看我的技能
Stop, you idiot!
住口,你這個笨蛋
Don't unsheathe it here!
別在這裡拔劍
Let go, old man!
老頭子,你放手
I want to go to battle!
我想要上戰場
This is the last straw, you idiot!
這是最後一根稻草,你這個白癡
This is...
現在是...
Shut up!
閉嘴
What shall we do, Your Majesty?
陛下,我們該怎麼辦?
I don't mind, Ketil.
我不介意,凱特爾
Let me see his swordsmanship.
讓我瞧瞧他的劍術
- What?
-什麼?
That pig will be tonight's dinner for the soldiers.
那頭豬會是士兵們今天的晚餐
Cut it as if it was a human.
把牠當成人砍殺吧
Yes... Here we go.
好的...我要上囉
Hey, what's wrong?
喂,怎麼搞的?
What is this?
這是怎麼回事?
What's happened?
發生了什麼事?
It's so loud.
好吵
Whose voice is this?
那是誰的聲音?
Stop. That's enough. I understand very well.
住手,夠了,我清楚了
Who knew bones... were so hard...?
誰知道骨頭會這麼硬?
Olmar, was it?
歐瑪,是嗎?
We will discuss your enrollment
我們會討論你的從軍事宜
as a thegn with the captain and inform you tomorrow morning.
成為首領之下的臣子 明早就會通知你
Until then, stay within Jelling.
在那之前,你就待在耶林吧
You really ruined it for us, Olmar.
一切都被你搞砸了,歐瑪
Everyone in the corps is going to make fun of me about this for a while.
我會因為這件事 被隊上的人嘲笑好一陣子
Jeez... The more cowardly they are,
天啊,這種膽小的人
the more unpredictable they become in critical situations.
在重要關頭反而會出現驚人之舉
Anyway, what's done is done.
總之,木已成舟
Just make sure you don't embarrass our family any more than this.
你最好別再做出比這個 更丟臉的事,讓家人蒙羞了
He's typical...
他很典型
He has no skill but has a big ego.
就是個無能的自大狂
He does not know his ability at all.
他完全沒有自知之明
People like him are the first to die on the battlefield.
像他這種人會最先死在戰場上
I wouldn't want him as a subordinate.
我絕不要他當我的部下
I understand your opinion as a captain.
這是你身為首領的看法,我明白
Now, let me hear your other opinion.
現在,你再說說另外的看法吧
That young man is very useful.
那個年輕人會很有用處
I agree. We can use him.
我同意,我們能夠利用他
He's a typical Nordic youth.
他是個典型的北方年輕人
A foolish one at that.
一個北方蠢蛋
He will do exactly what we want him to do.
我們說什麼,他都會照辦
So we'll go with that plan?
那麼,我們就照著計畫走?
Let it begin.
開始進行吧
I have yet to be enthroned, but this opportunity is too good to pass up.
我尚未登基,但我實在不能 錯失這個大好的機會
It is for the peace of the whole nation. Sorry, but I'll need you to cry.
這是為了國家的和平 抱歉了,但我需要你受苦
That man named Ketil
那個叫凱特爾的人
will be requisition number one.
會是我們第一個徵地的對象
"For Love That Was Lost."
為了失去的愛
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻譯:歐德慧